[
    {
        "question": "Q1: Which of the following is the correct syntax to print the message in C++ language?",
        "a": "cout <<\"Hello world!\";",
        "b": " Cout << Hello world! ;",
        "c": "Out << Hello world!;",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q2: Which of the following is the correct identifier?",
        "a": " $var_name",
        "b": " VAR_123",
        "c": " varname@",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q3: Which of the following is the address operator?",
        "a": " @",
        "b": " #",
        "c": " &",
        "d": " %",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q4: Which of the following features must be supported by any programming language to become a pure object-oriented programming language?",
        "a": " Encapsulation",
        "b": " Inheritance",
        "c": " Polymorphism",
        "d": " All of the above",
        "ans": "ans4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q5: The programming language that has the ability to create new data types is called___.",
        "a": " Overloaded",
        "b": " Encapsulated",
        "c": " Reprehensible",
        "d": " Extensible",
        "ans": "ans4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q6:Which of the following is the original creator of the C++ language?",
        "a": " Dennis Ritchie",
        "b": " Ken Thompson",
        "c": " Bjarne Stroustrup",
        "d": " Brian Kernighan",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q7:Which of the following is the correct syntax to add the header file in the C++ program?",
        "a": " #include < userdefined>",
        "b": " #include \"userdefined.h\" ",
        "c": " < include > \"userdefined.h \" ",
        "d": " Both A and B",
        "ans": "ans4"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q8:Which of the following is the correct syntax to read the single character to console in the C++ language?",
        "a": " Read ch()",
        "b": " Getline vh() ",
        "c": " get(ch) ",
        "d": " Scanf(ch)",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q9:Which of the following statements is correct about the formal parameters in C++?",
        "a": " Parameters with which functions are called",
        "b": " Parameters which are used in the definition of the function ",
        "c": " Variables other than passed parameters in a function ",
        "d": " Variables that are never used in the function",
        "ans": "ans1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q10:The C++ language is ______ object-oriented language.",
        "a": " Pure Object oriented",
        "b": " Not Object oriented",
        "c": " Semi Object-oriented or Partial Object-oriented ",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q11:Which of the following comment syntax is correct to create a single-line comment in the C++ program?",
        "a": " //Comment",
        "b": " /Comment/",
        "c": " Comment// ",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q12:C++ is a ___ type of language.",
        "a": " High-level language",
        "b": " Low-level language",
        "c": " Middle-level language ",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans3"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q13:For inserting a new line in C++ program, which one of the following statements can be used?",
        "a": " \\n",
        "b": " \\r",
        "c": " \\a ",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans1"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q14:Which one of the following represents the tab?",
        "a": " \\n",
        "b": " \\t",
        "c": " \\r",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans2"
    },
    {
        "question": "Q15:Which of the following refers to characteristics of an array?",
        "a": " An array is a set of similar data items",
        "b": " An array is a set of distinct data items",
        "c": " An array can hold different types of datatypes ",
        "d": " None of the above",
        "ans": "ans1"
    }
]